What the fuck, Caleb?
Oh, wait till you see
the shot I got.
You looked like you were gonna
shit a brick out sideways.
You could have taken
my head off.
It wouldn't have been a clean
decapitation
with these blades.
You'd just scramble
your face up real good.
Shouldn't you go see if
Jessica is feeling any better?
She'll be fine.
I gave her Klonopin
so she can sleep off whatever
the fuck is wrong with her.
Girl is such a pain
in the ass.
Jessica?
Hey.
How you feeling, cuz?
Since none of these other
friends of yours
bothered to show up,
can I take your car and escape
the hell of being stuck here
with your latest boyfriend?
Great chat.
You better wake up
in the next half hour
or I'm gonna be forced
to go drown
that brainless meat puppet's
sorry ass.
"The intense horror
of my nightmare came over me."
"I tried to draw back my arm
but the hand clung on
and a most melancholy
voice sobbed,
'Let me in.'"
"'Let me in!'"
"As it spoke,
I discerned, obscurely
a child's face
looking through the window."
"Finding it useless to attempt
shaking the creature off,
I pulled its wrist on to
the broken pane..."
Jess?
-"...and rubbed it
to and fro..."
-Please shut up.
"...till the blood ran down
and soaked the bedclothes."
"Yet still it wailed,
'Let me in!'"
Jessica!
Shit, shit, shit!
No, Jess. Jess? Jess?
Who's the brainless
meat puppet now?
Caleb.
What the fuck?
Oh, my God.
What the hell happened?
Jess?
Jessica?
What the fuck? What?
No, no, no...
Caleb!
No...
No, Caleb!
Caleb!
Beth!
Beth, you in there?
Just give me five, all right?
Brandon is losing his shit.
He can't find the Strat he won
in that arm wrestling contest
last night.
It's already tuned and racked
stage left
like I told you it was
half an hour ago.
You feeling all right
in there?
I'm fine.
Just go man your station.
I'll be back before
curtains up.
You got it, boss.
Have you seen my favorite
black t-shirt?
I need it for the Labor Day
protest tomorrow.
Mom?
You're not going to any
protest on your own.
Sophie's dad's taking us.
I've told you, like,
ten times already.
Remember?
Well, did you remember
to check the bathroom hamper?
Tell Danny
to turn the music down.
Mom says,
"Turn the music down!"
I could've done that myself!
Kassie, you better not have
my scissors.
Don't got 'em, Mom!
It's dirty.
Well, stick it in the laundry,
and I'll do it later.
You'll forget.
You always forget.
You know where
the washing machine is.
Hey, Bridget.
Mom's on nights
and we're watching
all the Freddy movies in a row.
-Even the shitty ones.
-There aren't any shitty ones.
So, you, um,
wanna come over and...
In your dreams.
Your boyfriends are weirdos.
You're the weirdo.
Kassie!
Big crowd in tonight, Dan?
-Get out, Bridge!
-I would, but--
Let me in!
Somebody get that, please!
All right, all right!
Boo!
Beth.
You bitch.
Surprise, sis.
When did you get into town?
I Uber'd straight here
from LAX.
Hmm.
You been sleeping?
You look like Mom.
Beats looking like a tampon.
You know, the downstairs
buzzer is totally busted.
I was able to walk in
right off the street.
Whole building's busted.
It's getting knocked
in a month.
You're kidding me.
Nope. We're out.
Have you guys found
a new place?
Not yet.
Shit, El. You and Jay
have been here forever.
Was Bangkok awesome?
Insane. Crazy, obsessive fans
over there.
Did you drink snake blood?
Hey,
that's culturally insensitive.
What about
monkey brain barbecue?
Oh, yeah.
That's so much better, Dan.
Who's your friend, Kass?
She's called Staffanie.
Oh. Hey, Staffanie.
What's her, uh, situation?
Danny told me that when this
building used to be a bank,
a teller got caught stealing
and hunged himself
and if you walk around
with coins in your pockets,
his ghost hears the jingle.
And he scares you to death
so he can take all your money.
It's true.
If he comes after me,
Staffanie will scare him
to death first.
Ghosts aren't real.
-Have you ever seen one?
-Mmm-mmm.
Then how do you know
they don't exist?
Because...
I only believe what I can see.
For me?
- It's for badass
rock chicks only.
Look, Mom. I'm a badass.
Please don't indoctrinate her
into your groupie world.
What's a groupie?
Your mom's favorite
nickname for me,
even though she knows
I'm a guitar technician.
If you say so.
Hey, be nice
or you don't get a gift.
Speaking of which,
check out what I got your dad.
What's going on, El?
Danny, go take my car and get
pizza with your sisters.
Sure thing, Mom.
I just can't wrap my head
around all this.
What, did he meet
someone else?
No. He believes paying
child support
equals co-parenting from afar.
Why didn't you tell me, El?
I would've jumped
right on a plane
to help you work through this.
I called you.
Twice.
First time, when he told me
he was leaving.
Second,
the night he moved out.
That was two and half
months ago, Beth.
I'm sorry, okay?
You know when I'm on the road,
I get sucked in deep
and I'm trying to make
chief tech right now.
And if I do,
I'll be the first woman
in my crew to do it, so...
Please, Ellie, we need
to talk this through properly.
El...
Look, you can sleep
on the sofa tonight
but I gotta pack and move.
Hey, Bethy-boo.
It's Ellie. Just...
calling to say hi. And, um...
me and Jay, we, uh...
You know what--
I don't blame you.
I hate the sound
of my voice too.
What's going on with you,
Beth?
I screwed up again,
like I always do.
And I need you to help me
figure it out.
Again.
What happened?
Mmm.
Hurry up, Bridge.
You wanna carry them?
You wanna get your license?
Come on, Kass.
Earthquake!
Come on.
Go!
Stay down!
Shit.
That was intense.
I think I peed my pants.
Is it warm?
Mmm-mmm.
It's probably just soda.
All right. Come on.
Holy shit.
Bridget, check this out.
What is it?
There's a hole.
Careful, Dan.
There could be aftershocks.
It's an old bank vault!
Danny, don't!
Dan?
Come on, Danny. Let's go!
Just hang on!
Danny!
Relax a minute, Bridge!
Danny, are you okay?
I'm fine.
Anything?
The network
is totally screwed.
I'm sure they're fine, El.
Hey.
Is everyone okay?
Anybody hurt?
Hey, Gabe.
The kids went to go get pizza
and I can't get through
on their cells.
Can I borrow your car
to go find them?
-How about I drive you?
-Thanks.
Let me get the keys.
-Who are you?
-Beth.
Ellie's sister.
Ah, yeah, yeah.
The groupie.
Let me ask you somethin'.
Can you hear her up there?
-What?
-Quake.
Sent her hiding in the ducts.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Let's roll.
Is that them?
Good to meet you.
You never take the elevator
after a quake.
Bridget dropped the pizza.
Oh, honey. I love you guys
so much more than pizza.
The magnitude 5.5 earthquake
hit just north
of the Puente Hills fault
less than an hour ago.
Jolting downtown Los Angeles
and everywhere from
La Habra to...
You think it might
be worth something?
Mom could do with some extra
money right now,
don't you think?
I don't think Mom wants cash
from something you stole.
It's not stolen.
It's probably been
locked in that vault forever.
Yeah, and weird shit like this
gets locked away for a reason.
Just leave it, Dan.
Argh! Fuck!
Let me see it.
It's just a nick.
Dan...
Danny, please close it.
I don't like this, Dan.
You need to put it back
right now.
Mom's not letting any of us
out the front door
again tonight.
First thing in the morning
then.
Promise me?
You going deep sea diving?
I gotta see under
before I get in.
I got stung by a jellyfish
at the beach before.
I don't like going underwater.
I don't think
there's any weird
sea creatures in the tub.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
It's a... It's a...
You okay?
I'm good, sweetie.
I hate when
my tummy hurts too.
Good afternoon,
my fellow clergymen.
I am Father Marcus Littleton,
the library keeper here
at Saint Patrick's Cathedral
and I welcome you all today
to the City of Angels.
You've been invited here
to witness the unveiling
of a unique artifact
that was discovered
by our overseas missionaries.
I would like to present
what I believe to be one of
the three fabled volumes
of Naturum Demento,
The Book of the Dead.
My tests to date have revealed
that its bindings
are made of cured human flesh,
its passages and etchings
inked in blood.
This is heresy!
Today,
I seek church approval
to translate
the spiritual mysteries
its pages undoubtedly hold.
Destroy it!
It's called The Book of
the Dead for a reason!
I seek to look at
this book for the good of man!
Rejected by
the elders of our church,
myself, Canon Damien Shanahan,
and Father Hugo Cortez
have been working in secret
to translate
The Book of the Dead's
myriad writings and glyphs.
Its pages contain ancient
rituals and incantations,
the recitation of which
proclaim to allow contact
with supernatural forces
that exist beyond the thin
veneer of our known world.
It is January 24th
in the year of our Lord, 1923.
And I,
Father Marcus Littleton,
shall now commence
reading aloud
the first of the spiritual
resurrection passages.
Hey!
Help!
Shut the fuck up!
It's okay. It's okay.
It's just a blackout.
Bridget?
You all right?
Yeah.
Looks like it's just us
that's out.
Really?
Mom?
El, are you sleeping?
Where is she?
Mom?
El?
What's up, sis?
I had the most
beautiful dream.
We were together,
sitting in a tall forest.
The wind was clean
and the birds were singing
the sweetest...
Melodies.
It was a perfect day
and all I could think about
was how much I wanted
to cut you all open
and climb inside your bodies
so that we could stay
one happy family.
It's in me.
Don't let it take my babies.
Mom!
Bridget, take her back inside.
Now!
What's wrong with her, Bridge?
Stairs. Go!
Go, go, go.
Come on.
Wake up, Ellie.
Come on, wake up.
Danny!
They're gone.
One minute she was fine
and the next
she was talking crazy and...
And now she's gone.
Network's still fucked.
May I pray?
She's not religious.
Wasn't.
It's just a few words.
Join me.
Eternal rest grant unto her,
O Lord
and let perpetual light
shine upon her.
May her soul
and the souls
of all the faithful departed
through the mercy of God--
What the hell happened
to her face?
Rest in peace.
Looks like someone
beat her up.
There's an old fire-escape
ladder
on the north side
of the building.
I could try to get down that,
raise the alarm,
get some help in here.
You have to go through 82.
Ah, shit.
That's unoccupied, right?
Yeah. Like most of this
condemned dump.
You got the tools?
We could just cut right
through the door.
In my truck.
You ain't gettin' through
those old doors
without something heavy-duty.
I want Dad to come home.
He will.
When we get the phones working
again, he'll come right back.
How do you know he will?
You said Mom
was gonna be okay.
I thought she would be.
I'm so sorry, Kass.
I'm gonna get my shotgun,
and we're gonna blast it open.
Just give me a minute, okay?
I don't like being trapped.
Everyone is on edge enough
without guns getting fired
in here.
I don't know what to do, El.
You're the one
who always has the answers.
I'm too scared to even face
your kids right now.
No matter how busy
you ever got,
you always found time for me.
For everyone.
I can't believe I'm never
gonna speak to you again.
Hey, Bethy-boo. It's Ellie.
Just... calling to say hi.
And, uh...
Beth.
Beth!
You have to help me, Beth.
You have to.
- I'm burning.
I'm burning alive!
El?
-Mom?
-She's alive?
She's burning up.
I'll get ice.
Mom?
Mommy's with the maggots now.
Mom, stop it!
Stop it!
It's not my fault, Bridget.
Get away from her, Bridge!
What's happening to me,
sweetheart?
I don't know, Mom.
I do.
I'm free now.
Free from all you
titty-sucking parasites.
Let me kiss it better.
Who wants to rot next?
Eeny...
meeny...
miny...
You.
Ellie?
Fuck!
Grab the cabinet.
Get away from the door.
Please, we need help!
Let me in!
Hello!
Can you hear me?
Don't you think Mom looks
just like one of those pictures
from that book?
Answer me, Danny.
You never should've stolen it.
This isn't my fault.
This is your fault!
- Get off me! Get off!
- Stop it!
-Hey! Hey, hey!
-This is all your fault!
Hey. Hey.
You don't turn on each other.
Ever.
I need to show you something.
What is this, Danny?
Does it hurt bad?
Bridget?
I'm okay.
♪ Gold-haired girls ♪
♪ With curling tresses ♪
♪ Hush-a-bye baby ♪
♪ Babe not mine ♪
♪ Mothers who nurse ♪
♪ With sad caresses ♪
♪ Hush-a-bye baby ♪
♪ Babe not mine ♪
Mom?
Beth?
I took these too.
There's this creepy priest
on them,
reading passages
from the book.
It's like a weird dark prayer.
And when he spoke the words...
Bridget's right.
This is all my fault.
Bridget...
♪ And black knife bring ♪
♪ To cross my sorrow ♪
♪ Hush-a-bye baby ♪
♪ Babe not mine ♪
Oh, there you are.
Hey there, cutie-pie.
What's wrong with you, Mom?
I was just feeling sad about
me and your dad.
But he's here now.
He came home to see us.
We're getting back together.
We love each other.
Isn't that right, my darling?
And we love you too.
Open up and let us in, Kassie.
We can be a big,
happy family again.
You don't look so good, Mom.
Oh.
Nothing a big old hug and kiss
from you won't fix.
Open up now,
like a good girl.
That's it.
Come on, now.
Do it for Mom and Dad.
Mom!
-You okay?
-I'm sorry.
I thought Mom was better.
Open the door
like you open your legs,
you stinking groupie slut!
I'm not a groupie,
you psycho bitch!
Beth.
Go to your room.
It'll be okay, Danny.
Staffanie will protect us.
Right?
Yeah.
What are you looking at, hon?
I gotta
kill the creepy-crawlies
that I got inside my tummy.
I don't like having things
inside my tummy.
Do you, Auntie Beth?
Hey.
Is this a nightmare?
It's just like a nightmare,
Kass.
Is what happened to Bridget
and Mom gonna happen to us?
I'm not gonna let that happen.
I promise.
You'd be a good mom someday,
Auntie Beth.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
You know how to lie to kids.
I thought I should tie her up.
Just in case.
I wanna listen to that vinyl.
It's too dangerous.
Those words...
Yeah, well, maybe
there's words on there
that can help stop
all of this.
We've got no power
to run a turntable.
I can fix that.
I listened to the first
and then he spoke the words
on the second.
I guess I'll start
at the other end, then.
Just in case.
It is now two nights
since I read aloud
from the book.
My want to understand and
commune with the other side
could not have been
more misguided.
I make this final recording
as a warning to whoever next
comes into contact
with its malignant pages.
Naturum Demento
cannot be destroyed.
When you find it, bury it deep
in our secret vault,
for the words I uttered have
unleashed a demonic entity
beyond my darkest nightmare.
Is Bridget gonna
come back like Mom?
I don't know, Kass.
The demon possessed
Cortez first,
rotting him
from the inside out.
With the might of
our Lord's words,
we tried to drive out
the foul entity
but it mocked our prayers
and took Shanahan
under its control.
Fellow priests
came to our aid
but the possession quickly
spread amongst them
without rhyme nor reason.
This evil is not governed
by the rules of man.
No, it takes its pleasure
in creating terror
through total chaos.
Desperate to end this curse,
I tried to kill what were once
my brothers.
I led them to the woodshed
and set it ablaze.
But they danced in its flame
and reveled in its burn.
Mr. Fonda's kitty hides up
there sometimes.
I don't think it's a cat.
I buried their
squirming, spitting corpses
in consecrated earth.
But they arose again,
rotting and rage-filled.
Careful, Danny.
After hiding
in the cellar for a night,
I knew only
one choice remained.
Complete bodily dismemberment.
Told you, you should've
put the book back, Danny.
I chopped, and I hacked,
and I...
I failed.
I can hear them
outside the doors now,
begging for me.
It is only a matter of time
before I am taken too.
Nothing can stop
this demonic force.
Even its final remnants
will come after you.
You must run.
All you can do is run!
This horror will not stop
until innocence is destroyed.
Until evil...
...be thy name.
Danny.
I'm sorry, Kass.
I will swallow your soul.
Two souls?
Please. El...
Ellie waits in hell for you
and your unborn bastard baby.
No.
Auntie Beth!
Are you hurt?
Are you gonna be a mom?
Yes.
And I'm getting us
out of here.
How?
Fire escape. Let's go.
Don't look back there.
Get back. Cover your ears.
Bethy-boo!
She's trying to take
your mommy away
from you, Kassie.
I know you're not my mom
anymore.
Don't take me from them.
You have no idea
what it's like
to bring a child into
this world, Beth.
That's my gun,
you thieving cunt.
Auntie Beth!
Everybody here
dies by dawn, Beth.
Run!
Dead by dawn!
-Dead by dawn!
-By dawn!
Dead by dawn!
Here.
No way out!
-Auntie Beth!
-Come here!
No!
Kassie. Kassie.
Kassie. Kassie. Kassie.
Am I dead?
Come on. Get in.
Kass, where's the beeper?
Come on. Come on.
It's coming.
Get under!
Kassie!
All I want
is your little head, baby girl.
Come get some.
Turn it on, Kass!
Please.
Help me, Bethy-boo.
Only my sister
gets to call me that.
You know, you really do
look like Mom.
And you're gonna fail
miserably just like her.
You stinking, horrible...
...groupie cunt!
There's been no cell signal
until, like, five minutes ago
and the thunder kept me awake,
so I got basically
less than zero sleep.
Anyway, all my early morning
moans aside,
we are still gonna have such
a fab weekend at the lake.
Caleb's dad's cabin
is so awesome,
and you're gonna absolutely
love his friends.
I'm sure one of them
will be perfect for you.
I don't mean to be
a downer or anything
but I was actually thinking
of taking a rain check
on this whole trip thing.
Not a chance.
I'm picking you up in 15.
Bye!